幕雨字幕组译制
翻译：Brynt&超威闫叔  校对：Brynt&超威闫叔
时间轴：花格子神尼&拜仁小攀  后期&特效：Brynt
一开始我也不相信
At first, I didn't believe it either.
但奥林匹斯诸神的确存在
But the gods of Olympus are real.
有时诸神会跟凡人结合
And sometimes, these gods have children with humans
他们的孩子被叫做混血儿
called half-bloods.
我就是其中一个
I'm one of them.
我是波西・杰克逊  海神波塞顿之子
I'm Percy Jackson. Son of Poseidon, god of the sea.
波西杰克逊与魔兽之海
七年前  四名混血儿结伴前往
Seven years ago,four of these children were headed to Camp Half-Blood
混血儿在凡间唯一的避风港-混血营
the only place on Earth that is safe for our kind.
但只有三个成功抵达
Only three of them made it.
我们快到混血营了
We're almost at camp!
小心
Look out!
格罗弗  卢克  帮帮他
Grover! Luke, help him!
格罗弗  你没事吧
Grover, are you okay?
我的腿卡住了
My leg. it's stuck.
快起来  我扶着你
Come on. I got you.
你们先走  我来拖住他们
Keep going. I'll hold them off.
不行  塔利亚（牧歌女神 司美三女神之一） 他们会杀了你的
No, Thalia. They'll kill you.
卢克  快走  我随后就来
Go, Luke. I'll be right behind you.
我在这儿呢
Over here!
安娜贝丝  快点
Annabeth, come on!
退后
Stay back.
塔利亚  赶快过来
Thalia, come on!
不  塔利亚
No! Thalia!
她叫塔利亚 为救其他三个人牺牲了性命
Her name was Thalia, and she gave her life to save three.
在塔利亚弥留之际...
And so, as Thalia lay dying...
她的父亲宙斯找到了另一种让她活下去的方法
her father Zeus found another way for her to live.
一个可以让所有混血儿都能存活下来的方法
A way for all half-bloods to live.
这件礼物确保了混血营里不会再出现这样的牺牲
A gift to ensure no one in Camp Half-Blood would die the same way.
这道壁障能保护他们所有人不受敌人的威胁
The barrier, to protect them from those who lived for their death.
快走吧
Let's go!
每一天  塔利亚的英勇事迹都激励着我
Every day, the story of Thalia's bra very inspires me.
她化作的树保护着我的家园
And her tree protects my home.
但不会总保证得了我安全
But not always my head.
你人真好  还特地跑来看我拨得头筹
How nice of you to show up just to watch me win.
你并不像他们说的那样  克拉丽丝
Everything they say about you is wrong, Clarisse.
其实你挺有幽默感的
You actually do have a sense of humor.
又挂了一个  波西  加油啊
There goes another one. Go, Percy!
加油啊  波西  我在你身上押了五十个金币呢
Come on, Percy! I got 50 drachma on you!
你拿波西下赌注了
You bet on this?
干嘛  你有意见吗
What, is that wrong?
九七年产的黑芙蓉（希腊北部名葡萄酒） 想尝尝吗
'97 Xinomavro. Would you like a taste?
你何苦折磨自己呢  狄俄尼索斯（酒神）
Why do you torture yourself, Dionysus?
我不就做错一件事
It was one transgression, one.
不就是个山湖仙女  还不是为了奥林匹斯才做的
And with a naiad, for the sake of Olympus.
我哪里知道宙斯中意她
How was I to know that Zeus had a thing for her?
更不会知道他居然会记恨这么久
Or that he could hold a grudge for so long?
既然宙斯永生不死
I think the fact that Zeus is immortal...
那他想记恨你多久都行
means there's no limit to how long he can hold a grudge.
基督教有个家伙可以把水变成酒
The Christians have a guy who can do this trick in reverse.
那样才算神呢
Now, that's a god.
你还没输够吗  杰克逊
Aren't you tired of getting beat, Jackson?
克拉丽丝
Clarissa!
救我  救救我
Help! Help me!
蒂留斯 抓住我的手
Tereus, grab my hand!
祝你好运吧
Good luck with that.
我抓住你了
I got you.
谢谢
Thank you!
波西
Percy!
克拉丽丝  克拉丽丝  克拉丽丝
Clarissa! Clarissa! Clarissa!
波西  我很好奇...
So, what I'm wondering is, Percy...
你的首次任务肯定是侥幸过关  对吧
that first quest you went on, beginner's luck, wasn't it?
克拉丽丝  是他救了奥林匹斯  光是这点就比你强一百倍
Clarisse, he saved Olympus. That's more than you've ever done.
管你们怎么说呢
Whatever.
虽然她是战神之女  但只是虚有其名
Even for the daughter of the god of war, that girl's a mythic bi...
别理她说的话  波西
Don't listen to her, Percy.
可是我已经都听了
You know, it's too late.
何况她说得还挺在理的
Besides, she has a point.
你说什么呢  老兄
Dude, what are you talking about?Man.
你不只是首战告捷而已
You're more than a one-quest wonder.
你还找回了阿瑞斯被偷的战车
You recovered Ares' stolen chariot.
不  事实上  那是克拉丽丝找回来的
No, actually, that was Clarissa.
好吧  那还有秋日竞赛 你可是技压群雄呢
Okay, what about the Fall Tournament? You owned that sucker.
也是克拉丽丝吗
Clarissa?
好吧  那至日比赛呢  还有寻访青铜龙呢
Okay, the Solstice Games? The Bronze Dragon's Quest?
谢谢你为我打气
Thank you for trying to cheer me up.
我宁愿去舔蹄子  也不想让你
I would lick a pair of cloven hooves...
去听克拉丽丝而不是我们的话
before I let you listen to Clarisse instead of us.
无意冒犯  格罗弗
No offense, Grover.
没关系  你是在暗示你想舔我蹄子吗
None taken. Is that an offer?
听着  克拉丽丝做过什么并不重要
Listen, it doesn't matter what Clarissa has done.
对奇戎（人首马身怪）和狄俄尼索斯老师来说你永远是最棒的
To Chiron and Mr. D, you're still the rock star.
派瑞（梨酒）・约翰逊
Perry Johnson!
我其实是叫波西・杰克逊  老师
Actually, it's Percy Jackson, sir.
差不多啦
Whatever.
我有件非常重要的事要交给你办
I have a very important task to entrust you with.
是吗
You do?
没错  这件任务非常重要  也很棘手
Yes, it's a critical assignment. And it's very taxing.
我可以信任你吗
Can I trust you?
当然可以
Of course.
很好  那你需要用这个
Good. You'll need this.
有时候这种活动会把地上弄得乱糟糟的
Sometimes these events get a little messy.
或许克拉丽丝说得对
Maybe Clarissa was right.
或许我能阻止卢克摧毁奥林匹斯
Maybe I only stopped Luke from destroying Olympus...
是因为我有安娜贝丝跟格罗弗帮我  对吗
because I had Annabeth and Grover helping me, right?
老爸
Dad?
波塞顿
Poseidon?
你有没有觉得你所做过的一切
Have you ever felt like everything you've ever done...
或许根本不是你自己的功劳呢
maybe you didn't really do it?
只是运气好而已
It was all just luck or something?
不  你当然不会这么觉得
No, of course not.
你是神
You're a god.
对凡人来说 这种感觉太难受了
Speaking as someone who's not, it sucks.
它会让你怀疑自己到底有没有那么厉害
It makes you question whether you were all that good to begin with.
好吧  很高兴又一次
Okay. Good not talking to you.
跟你单方面聊天
Again.
他就直接走进来了
So, he just walked right in?
他径直就走进混血营了
He just walked straight into camp?
事实上  他走得非常缓慢
It seems he lumbered, actually.
他就是大摇大摆走进来我也管不着
I don't care if he sashayed!
要是谁都能进来  那这个神之壁障还有什么用
What's the point of having this mystical protective barrier if any thing can just...
别动那瓶酒好吗  那可是珍贵的格连纳什葡萄酒
Could you not touch that, please? That's a very precious Grenache.
我觉得重点是
I think the point is...
既然他能直接通过塔利亚树的屏障
since he did pass right through the barrier from Thalia's tree...
- 不许再说了  - 那就说明他也是神裔
- Don't say it. - It means he's most likely a god-spawn.
好吧  但他到底是哪个神的后裔
Yeah, but the spawn of which god?
我知道
I know.
是波塞顿的
Poseidon.
狄俄尼索斯老师找你干嘛  别他叫过去肯定没什么好事
So, why did Mr. D summon you? It's not good to get summoned.
肯定没事儿的
I'm sure it's fine.
我敢肯定你要是没犯事儿的话
I'm sure you don't get summoned
是肯定不会被叫到大厅去的
to the Big House without a major-league screw-up.
我才没犯什么事儿呢
I didn't screw up.
我打扫了整个体育馆  还用吸尘器吸了一遍
I cleaned the entire coliseum. And vacuumed.
别听他瞎扯淡  好吗
Don't let him get into your head, okay?
有人死定了  有人要死定了  就我旁边那个
We have a dead camper walking. Dead camper walking, here.
谢了  还真是患难见真情呢
Thanks. This is friendship.
我就开个小玩笑  跟你闹着玩的呢
I'm just playing, just trying to have a little fun.
没关系
It's all right.
要是你被踢出去了  你的小屋可以归我吗
So, it's okay if I get your cabin when you get kicked out?
别担心  就狄俄尼索斯老师而已
Seriously, don't worry. it's just Mr. D.
又不是奇戎老师找你  他找你才...
I mean, if Chiron had summoned you, then...
好吧  你这回真死定了
You are so massively screwed.
不管你怀疑什么是我干的  我绝对没有干
Whatever it is you think I did, I didn't do it.
波西  你没做错什么事
You've done nothing, Percy.
没错
Exactly.
大家都认为你是波塞顿唯一的继承人
As you know, you are believed to be Poseidon's only heir.
是这样没错  那又如何
Yeah, so?
貌似现在这个观点不太正确
So, it would seem that belief has been held in error.
等等  你是说波西有个兄弟吗
Hold on. You're saying Percy has a brother?
或者是姐妹
Or a sister.
不是吧  波塞顿又多了个混血儿
Holy Styx. Another Poseidon half-blood.
也不完全算是这样
Not exactly.
严格说来  泰森算不上是个混血儿
Technically, Tyson is not a half-blood.
因为混血儿有一半血统是人
Half-bloods are half-human, hence the name.
我不懂你的意思
I don't get it.
如果新来那小子另一半不是人  那他另一半是是什么
If this new kid is not half-human, then what other half is he?
宁芙（希腊神话中精灵一族）  海宁芙
Nymph. Sea nymph.
神一旦跟宁芙结合  便会生出...
And when you cross a deity with a nymph, you get...
别碰这个  这可是琼瑶浆（葡萄酒的一种）
Don't touch. it's a Gewurztraminer.
嗨
Hi.
你好  哥哥
Hi, Brother.
你是这里的大人物  对吧  你拯救了世界之类的
So, you're the big shot here, right? You saved the world and stuff.
对  没错
Yeah. Yeah.
他们在你的饭里洒了胡椒
Hey. they put peppers in yours.
你还吃吗
Are you gonna eat that?
你吃吧
Go ahead.
他在耍我吗
Is he messing with me?
我觉得他是饿极了
I think he's hungry.
不是说他  我是说波塞顿
No, not him. I meant Poseidon.
他是在跟我开玩笑吗
Is this supposed to be some kind of joke?
一个同父异母弟弟  独眼巨人  别扯淡了
A half-brother? A Cyclops? Come on.
我觉得官方用语应该称之为"眼部受损"
I think the politically correct term is "ocularly impaired."
有个同父异母的弟弟总比什么都没有强
And a half-brother is better than nothing.
我喜欢有个兄弟
I like having a brother.
老爸带我来的
Dad was cool to bring me here.
老爸吗  老爸带你过来的
Dad? Dad brought you here?
我当时在北部的森林里
I was upstate, in the woods.
突然有一天  我的头顶上出现三叉戟  然后它又开始向南移
One day, this trident shows up over my head,and then it started moving south.
于是你就跟着它  一直跟到这里
And you followed it. You followed it here.
它发着光呢
It glowed.
看来有人有新兄弟了哦
Well, somebody has got a new brother.
他的双眼长得挺像他老爸的嘛
And I can see he's got his daddy's eyes.
不对
Well...
应该是独眼才对
"Eye."
你真该替他弄点喷雾过来
You should really get him some sprayable mist.
不管怎么说  这个点还挺有意思的  你说呢
Anyway, it is kind of interesting timing, don't you think?
或许波塞顿决定再要一个儿子是想...
Maybe Poseidon decided he needed another son to, you know...
来代表他
represent.
荒谬（公牛）
Bull.
你说什么
Excuse me?
有公牛的味道
Smells like bull.
壁障那儿出事儿了
We got barrier action.
克里斯  你不去吗
Hey, Chris, you coming?
算了  我不想去
No, I'm good.
太壮观了
That is so awesome.
没事的  壁障挺得住
It's chill. The barrier is holding.
科尔基斯公牛
A Colchis bull.
快跑
Run!
波西
Percy!
快起来
Come on!
- 我们得找到它的弱点  - 它有弱点吗
- We have to find its weak spot. - Does it have one?
波西  你去引开它
Percy, distract it for me.
我来搞定你
I got this.
坏牛儿
Bad bull.
看招  你这堆破铜烂铁
Hey, rust bucket!
可恶  杰克逊
Damn it, Jackson.
你知道科尔基斯公牛有多难找吗
Do you have any idea how hard Colchis bulls are to come by?
或许下一次想溺死别人的时候
Maybe next time you try to drown someone...
得先确定那个人是否是会游泳的半人半神
you'll first make sure he's not a demigod who can swim.
卢克
Luke?
事实证明  你不是唯一一个杀不死的混血儿
Turns out, you're not the only half-blood who's hard to kill.
预言嘛
You know, prophecy.
什么预言  你在说些什么
What prophecy? What are you talking about?
你还不知道吗
You don't know?
是吗
Huh.
奇戎对你隐瞒的事看样子又多了一条
Add that to the long list of things your buddy Chiron hasn't shared with you.
奇戎  狄俄尼索斯  还有其他人
Chiron, Mr. D, all the rest...
他们根本就不在乎我们
they don't care about us.
对他们来说  我们只是乳臭未干的小子
To them, we're just kids.
一堆随意使唤随便欺负的小卒而已
A bunch of pawns meant to be pushed around, told what to do.
我不是唯一一个有这种想法的混血儿
I'm not the only half-blood who thinks so.
仔细想想吧
Think about it.
我错过什么了
What did I miss?
波西呢
Where's Percy?
我最后一次看到他时  他正被科尔基斯公牛拖着走
Last time I saw him, he was getting dragged by a Colchis bull.
喂 叫你呢
Hey, you.
你怎么没被烤熟
How come you aren't barbecued?
独眼巨人是不怕火的
Cyclopes are fireproof.
那头牛是怎么穿过壁障的
How did the bull get through the barrier?
天呐
Oh, my gods.
中毒了
Poisoned.
那她...这棵树死了吗
Is she... ls the tree dead?
暂时没有  但离死也不远了
No, but dying.
大家很快就会适应这种状况的
A condition we're about to become all too familiar with.
各位 我们需要守卫轮班巡逻营区
Everybody,we're going to need a guard detail to patrol the perimeter.
感觉就像她又死了一回一样
It feels like she's dying all over again.
谁会做得出这种事儿
Who would do this?
是卢克  是他下的毒
Luke poisoned the tree.
波西
Percy!
太好了 你还没死呢
Yay, you're alive.
对  不只是我没死
Yeah, I'm not the only one.
卢克放那头牛进来的
Luke let the bull in.
没了树形成的壁障
Without the tree's barrier...
他就觉得外面有足够的半泰坦
he probably figures there's enough
能帮他达成所愿
demi-Titans out there to get him what he wants.
那他到底想要什么
And that would be what, exactly?
歼灭我们所有人  拉吕小姐
Our annihilation, Ms. La Rue.
歼灭所有混血儿
Our annihilation.
解药药效如何
How's the antidote coming?
非常缓慢
Slowly.
我知道现在或许时机不对
I know this probably isn't the best time...
但我必须要问你一件事
but there's something I have to ask you.
什么事
What is it?
卢克说有一个预言
It was something Luke said about a prophecy...
而且预言里提及到我
how I'm mentioned in it.
你知道这件事吗
Do you know anything about this?
知识不见得就是力量  波西
Knowledge isn't always power, Percy.
有时候  知识是一种负担
Sometimes, it's a burden.
这我知道
I know that.
但正如你所说  最近我的状态不怎么佳
But like you said, I've been pretty unexceptional lately.
这让我很疑惑我到底能不能实现预言
It's got me wondering if I'm prophecy-worthy.
人说  若是诸神想要折磨我们
They say that when the gods wish to torture us...
便会回应我们的祈祷
they answer our prayers.
哈耳摩尼亚之项链  赫拉克勒斯之弓  金苹果
Necklace of Harmonia, Hercules' bow, Golden Apple of Discord.
三千年来神与半人半神的智慧都不能...
Three millennia of gods and demigods...
你还以为有谁能想出办法治好塔利亚之树
you'd think that someone would have come up with a cure for Thalia's tree.
波尔赛弗捏（冥王哈迪斯之妻）提出用美乐棵（园艺品牌） 或许我们能试试
Persephone did come up with Miracle-Gro. Maybe we can try that.
就是这个
That's it.
这个
Right here.
那个治不好塔利亚之树  反而只会害死大家
That is not gonna cure Thalia's tree so much as get us all killed.
尤其是我
Me, in particular.
这个正是我们需要的  绝对能行得通
It's perfect. it's exactly what we need.
我要拿给狄俄尼索斯老师看
I'm taking this to Mr. D.
不行
No.
我本来想再多帮你兜一会儿这重担  但既然你都知道了  那就进去吧
I was hoping to spare you this onus a little while longer, but go inside.
去楼上的阁楼
Upstairs, to the attic.
你下来之后  我们再谈其他的事儿
And when you come back down, we'll talk some more.
当然前提是你还没疯的话
Assuming you're still sane, that is.
我是德尔菲（希腊古都）之灵
I am the spirit of Delphi...
腓尼基・阿波罗预言的先知
speaker of the prophecies of Phoebus Apollo...
巨蟒之屠夫
slayer of the mighty Python.
过来吧  探求者  说出你的问题吧
Approach, seeker, and ask.
听说有一个关于我的预言
I heard there was a prophecy about me.
是的
Aye.
但在你知晓未来前  得先了解过去
But before you learn the future, know first the past.
很久很久以前  在此时代之前
Long ago, before our time...
在奥林匹斯与诸神出现之前
before Olympus and the gods...
以克隆那斯为首泰坦
Titans ruled the world.
统治着当时的世界
Led by Kronos...
他是一股非常邪恶的势力  吞食了自己的子女
a force so evil, he devoured his own children.
但他其中三个儿子逃过一劫
But three of his sons escaped.
也就是后来的宙斯  哈迪斯以及波塞顿
Zeus, Hades and Poseidon.
他们消灭了克隆那斯
They destroyed Kronos...
并将他的遗体放逐至冥界至深至暗之深渊
and banished his remains to the depths of Tartarus.
但克隆那斯注定将会再度归来
But Kronos is fated to rise again...
并对奥林匹斯与世界进行复仇
to exact his vengeance on Olympus, and the world.
只有三大主神的一个混血后裔才能打败他
Only one half-blood child of the three eldest gods can defeat him.
这个孩子能成为我们的救世主
This child shall be our salvation...
但也可能会导致我们灭亡
or the cause of our destruction.
这一切都源于两个相互争夺金羊毛的表亲
It all begins when two cousins grapple for a fleece...
海神之子与盗火之人
the son of the sea and the lightning thief.
是卢克
Luke.
而那个三大主神的混血后裔
And that half-blood of the eldest gods...
会冲破一切阻碍活到二十岁
shall reach 20 against all odds.
“目睹世界陷入无尽沉睡”
"And see the world in endless sleep...
“诅咒之剑将会夺取邪恶之灵”
"the evil soul, cursed blade shall reap.
“唯一的抉择将会终结他的使命”
"A single choice shall end his days...
“并决定奥林匹斯的存亡”
"Olympus to preserve or raze."
那个亡字是毁灭的意思
And that is "raze" with a as in "destroy."
我问过了
l asked.
有没有一丝丝可能
Is there any chance, any chance at all...
或许我不是预言所提及之人
that I might not be the guy in the prophecy?
神谕提到的是一个三大主神的混血后裔
The Oracle references a half-blood of the eldest gods.
而你是宙斯  哈迪斯以及波塞顿三神仅存的混血子嗣
You are the only living half-blood heir of Zeus, Hades or Poseidon.
预言所指的只可能是你
The prophecy could refer only to you.
要是因我能力不足没能拯救得了奥林匹斯
What if I destroy Olympus...
反而导致了其灭亡该怎么办
by not being good enough to save it?
问题就出在这儿  不是吗
That seems to be the question, doesn't it?
绝对不行
It's absolutely out of the question.
要是你能听我哪怕说一刻都行
If you could just listen to me for one moment...
我是在听你说的啊  你想出去执行任务
I am listening. You want to go on a quest.
今天一定到礼拜四了
It must be Thursday.
我是认真的  我敢肯定这方法能行的通
I'm serious. I'm absolutely sure that this is gonna work.
这酒存的年份恰到好处
It was such a good year.
金羊毛能治愈任何活的生物
The Golden Fleece can heal any living person or thing...
其中就包括塔利亚之树
including Thalia's tree.
治好了树的话  我们的壁障也能够恢复
We heal the tree, we restore the barrier around camp.
我很惊讶你居然想跟她一起去  安德雪特（衬衣）先生
I'm surprised you want to go along with her on this, Mr. Undershirt.
是安德伍德
Underwood.
随便啦
Whatever.
去寻找金羊毛的羊男没一个能活命的
Every satyr who has ever gone after the Fleece has died.
对吧  我早就跟她说过了
Right? I mentioned that to her.
但为了混血营  我甘愿冒险
But it's a risk I'm willing to take for the good of the camp.
听着  我最后一次听说
Look, the last I heard...
金羊毛时  它在魔兽之海
the Golden Fleece was in the Sea of Monsters...
凡人将其称之为百慕大三角
what the humans call the Bermuda Triangle.
那是个不仅是羊男该害怕的地方
A place not only a satyr should be afraid of.
所以我的答复是“不行” 绝对不行  抱歉  安娜贝儿
So, the answer is no. No. I'm sorry, Annabelle.
是安娜贝丝
Annabeth.
管它呢  这主意烂透了
Whatever. it's a terrible idea.
我有个很棒的主意
I've had a grand idea.
除非塔利亚之树能被治好
Unless Thalia's tree can be cured...
营区的壁障能被恢复
and the protective barrier around our camp restored...
否则每个半人半神  半人马  羊男  还有宁芙
then every demigod, centaur, satyr and nymph...
都会在数日内被杀死  甚至会更快
will be killed within days, if not sooner.
你还好吗
Hey, you okay?
别担心  混血营不会有事的
Don't worry, camp will be okay.
你得有信心  好吗
You have to have faith, right?
幸好  我已经考虑过这件事了
But fortunately, I have considered the matter.
在经过非常努力的钻研之后
And after great study...
我发现了唯一能够解救塔利亚之树
I have determined that the only thing that has the power to save Thalia's tree...
从而解救我们家园的方法
and therefore our home...
就是是传说中的金羊毛
is the Golden Fleece of myth...
什么
What?
只要它轻轻一碰
...whose touch...
所以的生物都能顷刻被治愈
...can heal every person and every thing.
所以  我们来一场仁慈的任务  当然前提是你们自愿
So, a quest, a mission of mercy, if you will...
进入未知而致命的水域
into uncharted and deadly waters...
我们的生存就是最大的赌注
with nothing less at stake than our own survival.
众所周知  羊男会自然受到金羊毛力量的吸引
Now, a satyr is naturally drawn, as you know, to the power of the Fleece.
因此  这场任务一定要由一个羊男来指引混血儿
And therefore, it must be a satyr who will guide a half-blood on this quest.
真是感激不尽啊
Thanks a lot.
伊克那提
Ichneutae!
你愿意指引我们的勇士吗
Will you guide the champion?
当然行
Oh, yeah.
很好  非常好  太棒了
Good. Great! That's great!
好~
Yeah!
至于勇士  在这困境中当然需要最厉害的英雄
As to who that champion might be, our plight calls for only our finest hero.
我们当中最优秀  最坚强同时也是最勇敢之人
The best of us, the strongest and the bravest.
战神的后裔
The scion of the god of war...
克拉丽丝
Clarissa!
太好了
Yes!
多谢大家
Thank you.
她的名字他倒是没念错
Her name, he gets right.
嘿  克拉丽丝  克拉丽丝
Hey, Clarissa. Clarissa!
干嘛
What?
你别老是杞人忧天  杰克逊
Don't worry about always coming in second, Jackson.
会养成习惯的
You do get used to it.
对吧  很明显我是不会知道啦
I think, right? Obviously, I wouldn't know.
听我说  卢克还在外面
Listen, Luke is still out there.
不知怎么回事  他也卷进金羊毛的事了
He's involved with the Fleece somehow...
我有预感他绝对不会罢手
and I've got a feeling that he's not done yet.
是吗
Really?
因为我可是觉得我貌似一点也不关心
Because I've got a feeling that I don't really care.
天呐  别总装出一副受伤的模样
Gosh, don't look so wounded.
听着  有的人生来就是将军命  而某些人只有一辈子当小卒的份
Listen, there are generals, and there are foot soldiers.
你能进得了军队就已经是万幸了
And you should feel lucky that you even made it into the army at all.
别在我不在的时候添乱子就行  好吗
Just try not to screw up anything too badly while I'm gone. Okay?
走吧
Let's go.
“诅咒之剑将会夺取”
"Cursed blade shall reap."
预言要是让人搞不懂的话还有什么用
What good is a prophecy if you can't even understand it?
我猜你肯定也没有答案  老爸
I guess you don't have any answers either, Dad.
这是你的剑
This was your sword.
这主意烂透了
This is a bad idea.
你都不知道我到底要说什么
You don't even know what I was gonna say.
你肯定要说你要去找金羊毛来解救混血营
You were going to say that you're going after the Fleece to save the camp.
事实上  他是要说“我们”一起去找金羊毛
Actually, he was gonna say "we" were.
听着  我知道你到底要干嘛
Look, I get what you're doing here.
你在担心你你首战告捷是侥幸的事儿
You're worried about the one-quest wonder thing...
你想证明自己的实力
and you want to make your bones.
可是伊克那提跟克拉丽丝已经出发去找金羊毛了
But lchneutae and Clarisse are already going after the Fleece...
扰乱别人的任务可不是君子所为
and it's not cool to bogart on someone else's quest.
我认为这也是我的任务
I think this is my quest, too.
神谕说他跟卢克要竞争金羊毛
The Oracle says he wrestles Luke for the Fleece.
是争夺  而且她还说
"Grapples." But she also said...
我注定了要么摧毁奥林匹斯  要么拯救它
that I'm destined to destroy Olympus, or save it.
显然拯救更好咯
Saving is better, obviously.
对啊
Yeah.
让我收拾下行李  在确定下我买好保险没有
Let me pack a bag and make sure my health insurance is paid up.
我们要怎么绕过他们而不被发现
How are we gonna get past them?
我想他们要找的是想进来的威胁
I think they're looking for threats trying to come in...
而不是想溜出去的家伙
not people trying to sneak out...
所以我们只要行事轻一点就行了
so, I think we're cool as long as we stay quiet.
抱歉
Sorry!
我们...
We're...
我们也在看守
We're guarding, too.
你们丢下我就跑了
You left without me.
泰森  我们要去的地方十分危险
Tyson, where we're going, it's very dangerous.
我知道   我又不笨
I know. I'm not stupid.
对  你只是蠢而已
No,just dumb.
我想帮忙
I want to help.
换做你的话你也会帮我的
You'd do it for me.
我很感激你...
I appreciate that...
但我觉得你不了解其中的危险性
but I don't think you understand exactly how dangerous this is going to be.
我了解
I do.
金羊毛被波吕斐摩斯（独眼巨人）看守着
The Fleece is guarded by Polyphemus.
你说谁
Who?
波吕斐摩斯
Polyphemus.
他算是比较知名的独眼巨人了
Closest thing Cyclopes have got to someone famous.
他抓走过奥德修斯（《奥德赛》一书中主角） 住在赛西兰
Captured Odysseus. Lives in Circeland.
等等  赛西兰吗
Wait, Circeland?
就修在他的岛上
Built on his island.
说来话长了
Long story.
关键是  我说不定能跟他沟通沟通
Point is, maybe I can talk to him.
就独眼巨人间的对话
You know, Cyclops to Cyclops.
不行  因为我不想跟独眼巨人一起去
No, you can't, because I'm not going with a Cyclops.
那就难办了  要是没有独眼巨人我也不去
Then we got a problem, because I'm not going without one.
波吕斐摩斯杀死了近乎所有接近金羊毛的羊男
This Polyphemus is probably what killed every satyr that's gone near the Fleece.
你要我带你去找一个独眼巨人  这没问题
You want me to lead you to a Cyclops? Fine.
但我得自己多带一个人作保护
But I'm bringing along one of my own, for protection.
门都没有
No way.
不行
No.
你觉得哪个会更引人注意
What do you think's gonna attract more attention...
是噪音还是独眼
all the noise or the one eye?
放过他吧  好吗
Just give the guy a break, okay?
好吧
Okay, fine.
小声一点
Keep it down.
这玩意儿超难搞到的
This is crazy hard to come by...
我可是为了以防紧急状况才带来的
and I only brought it along in case of an emergency...
我想这就是所谓的紧急状况  所以... 这个给你
which I guess this is an emergency, so... here.
喷雾
Mist?
它可以让你这样的家伙看起来正常点
It makes the mystical look normal.
“副作用可能包括英俊  头痛”
"Side effects may include handsomeness,
“有自尊心跟自尊低落”
headache, self-esteem and low self-esteem."
你要知道要不是混血营有危险
And just know that if the camp wasn't in danger...
我才不会浪费在你身上
I wouldn't be wasting this on you.
浪费什么
Wasting what?
效果不怎么持久  所以你得随时准备好再喷
It's not gonna last forever. You're gonna have to reapply it.
彻底改头换面了哦
Extreme makeover alert.
我看起来如何
How do I look?
长得还真跟老爸就几分像
A bit like Dad, actually.
他仍然还是个独眼巨人
He's still a Cyclops.
格罗弗  我们要往哪走  你闻到什么了吗
Grover, where are we going? What does your nose say?
佛罗里达沿岸某处  朝南走
Somewhere off the coast of Florida. South.
在这里
Over here.
安妮  嘿
Annie! Hey!
这是地狱战车
It's the Chariot of Damnation.
看来像纽约的出租车
Looks like a New York City cab.
确实没什么区别
Same difference.
不收现金  不收信用卡  只接受德拉克马（古希腊银币名）
No dollars, no credit cards. Drachmas only.
准备好零钱
Exact... Change... Please.
快点  快递  快上车
Chop, chop! Get in the cab.
为了保护乘客的健康  车子消毒过了
We just had this cab sanitized for your protection.
不过不是今年做的
It wasn't this year, though.
不好意思  我们想去佛罗里达
Excuse me, we're trying to get to Florida.
我们就喜欢这种路费  有赚头
Our kind of fare. Pricey.
大家好  我是该尼墨德  宙斯的司酒人
Hey, there. This is Ganymede, cupbearer to Zeus.
每当我出门替天神买酒时
And when I'm out buying wine for the lord of the skies...
一定会记得系好安全带
I always remember to buckle up.
或许我们应该搭飞机去
Maybe we should have flown commercial.
小心
Look out!
冷静点  要是我们不清楚自己在做什么
Calm down. If we didn't know what we were doing...
我们就拿不到驾照的
We wouldn't be licensed.
她们没有眼睛
They don't have eyes.
对啊
Yeah.
我知道  照片拍得很丑  头发也很丑
I know, awful picture. Bad hair day.
我们三人其实是有一只眼睛的
We do so have an eye.
肯定就在这儿附近
It's around here somewhere.
我最后一次看到时  你放在杂物箱里  愤怒婆
The last time I saw it, you put it in the glove compartment, Anger.
不许用那种口气叫我名字
Don't use that tone with my name.
这次她没放在那儿
It's not there this time.
胡蜂婆总爱把眼睛跟钥匙摆在一起
Wasp always puts it with the keys.
- 这只眼睛视力可是达到2.0呢  - 我的也是
- And it's 20,20. - So is mine!
眼睛难道不该给开车的人吗
Shouldn't the driver get the eye?
她用不着啦
She'll be fine.
暴风婆  快把车分开
Tempest, split!
波西
Percy!
这个功能可是可是需要多付费的哦
We paid extra for that option.
那小子说的对  眼睛应该交给司机才对
The kid is right. The driver should have the eyeball.
他真他娘的是个天才
He's a freaking genius!
把它塞进帽檐的人可是你
You're the one that put it in the visor.
说到这  很久没轮到我戴眼睛了
While it's on the table, I haven't had a turn in quite some time.
你故意的对吧
Oh, no, you didn't!
对  我就故意的
Yes, I did.
至少要扶着方向盘  好吗
Hands on the wheel at least, okay?
- 我们全死定了  - 安静
- We're all gonna die! - Pipe down.
预言不是说你至少会活到二十吗
Didn't that prophecy say you're gonna make it till at least 20?
你知道预言的事
You know about the prophecy?
当然  神谕是我们的朋友
Sure. The Oracle is a friend.
我们是死党  永远的好朋友
We're besties. B-F-F!
眼睛  眼睛  眼睛
EVE! Eye! Eye!
好恶心  快拿开
Gross! Get it off me!
你们对预言的事儿了解有多少
What do you know about the prophecy?
不要
No!
好吧  好吧
Okay, okay.
三十  三十一  七十五  十二
30. 31, 75,12.
什么
What?
波西  你得到你想要的答案了
Percy, you got your answer!
我只听到一堆数字
All I got were numbers.
对  到时候
Yes. You'll know...
你自然会知道的
When it matters.
我觉得我们的钱好像不太够诶
I think we're a little short on drachmas.
什么
What?
你们认为我们做的是什么
What do you... think we're... running here?
慈善吗
A charity?
给我下车
Get your cheap butts... Out!
刚刚实在是太...
That was...
我知道
I know.
太赞了  我们能再坐一次吗
Awesome! Can we go again?
这里绝对不是佛罗里达
We're definitely not in Florida.
我觉得我们在奥林匹斯
I think we're in Olympus.
向伟大的宙斯致敬  请原谅我们擅自闯入奥林匹斯
Hail to you, great Zeus! Forgive our trespass on Olympus.
我们在找交通工具去佛罗里达
We're seeking transport to Florida.
宙斯
Zeus?
别喊了  快停下  这里不是奥林匹斯 好吗
Whoa, stop it, stop it, stop it! This isn't Olympus, okay?
这是国会大厦
This is the Capitol building.
我们在华盛顿呢  好吗
We're in Washington, D.C. Okay?
看起来真像奥林匹斯
It looks like Olympus.
这些有权有势的家伙也只关心自己而已
Right down to the dudes with power who only care about themselves.
我们得找个汽车站
We need to find a bus station.
我们还是先弄点钱吧
First we need to get some money.
你好  混血儿帐户贵宾
Hey,there, valued half-blood account holder!
申请新的阿佛洛狄忒（美神）专用信用卡  你就能...
Sign up for our new Aphrodite Express credit card, and you can...
请给我四杯大拿铁  咖啡因减半  不加奶泡
Can I get four venti half-caf no-whip lattes?
多加一份花蜜
And an extra shot of nectar.
花蜜
Nectar?
你要是没试过这种喝法就算是妄在世上走一遭了  老兄
If you haven't had, then you haven't lived, buddy.
赫拉顿希尔
Hecatonshire.
嘿
Hey.
看得出你现在很忙
I see you got your hands full.
加奶油吗
Room for cream?
加花蜜  双份
Nectar. Double shot.
这辈子值了
I've lived.
我从没这么开心过
This might be the most fun I've ever had.
从来没有
Ever.
当然  怎么都比住在森林里好吧  对吧
Yeah, anything's gotta be better than living in the woods, right?
要是你也跟我一起的话都还好啦
Living in the woods would have been fine if you were there.
有个兄弟什么事儿都好起来的
Everything's better with a brother.
严格说来  我们的妈妈不是同一人
You know, technically, we don't have the same mom.
但我们却依然还是兄弟  这样多酷啊
So we're still brothers! I know! How cool is that?
就跟北极一样
Arctic.
你不觉得太甜了吗
It's too sweet, don't you think?
不会  花蜜永远都不嫌甜
No, nectar's never too sweet.
放开我
Get off me!
- 放开我  - 格罗弗
- Get off me! - Grover!
波西
Percy!
- 可恶  - 那是克里斯・罗德里格斯吗
- Damn! - Was that Chris Rodriguez?
他们怎么做到的
How did they do that?
在混血营里卢克曾经说过有其他混血儿叛变了
Back at camp, Luke said that there were other half-bloods who turned.
你说叛变是什么意思
What do you mean, "turned"?
倒戈相向了
To his side.
卢克现在手上有格罗弗
Luke has Grover.
神谕是对的
The Oracle was right.
卢克要去找金羊毛  所以他才需要一个羊男
Luke is going after the Fleece. That's why he needs a satyr.
可是卢克要金羊毛干嘛
But what does Luke want with the Fleece anyway?
我也不清楚
I don't know.
如果我们想把格罗弗找回来  就得先找到卢克
But if we're gonna get Grover back, we need to find Luke.
可是我们不知道他在哪儿
But we don't know where he is.
我知道谁知道了  快点  走了
I know someone who does. Come on.
什么  你想把我们自己连夜快递到魔兽之海吗
What, are we shipping ourselves overnight express to the Sea of Monsters?
你不是想找卢克吗  他老爹肯定知道他的下落
You want to find Luke? His dad will know where he is.
这里是奥林匹斯包裹服务 快点
Olympic Parcel Service. Come on.
岂止喜欢  他会爱死它的
Like it? He'll love it.
没错  赫菲斯托斯（铁匠之神）的工作质量很高的  现在的人完全比不了
Yes, Hephaestus does do quality work. Everyone else these days, hacks.
不好意思  我们想找赫尔墨斯
Excuse me, we're looking for Hermes.
作为明显之神我很抱歉  但是我现在有客人
I'm sorry to be the god of obviousness, but I'm with a customer.
你想明天一早就送到哈迪斯手上需要两百五十德拉克马
You want an overnight shipment to Hades, that will be 250 drachmas.
非常好  谢谢惠顾
Perfect. Thank you, sweetness.
我会帮你留意的  下周见
I will take care of that for you, and I'll see you next week.
好了 各位
Now, you.
你们要找赫尔墨斯吗
You are here about Hermes?
其实我们是找他儿子来着   事态紧急
His son, actually. It's kind of important.
看你风风火火闯进来的样子我就知道
Yeah, I could tell the way you burst in here, all rude-like.
他儿子名叫卢克・卡斯特兰
His son's name is Luke Castellan.
我那任性的儿子又惹什么事了
What has that wayward boy of mine gotten himself into now?
等等  你是...
Wait, you're...
赫尔墨斯
Hermes.
你们没认出我来真是太侮辱人了
Little insulted you didn't recognize me.
要不是我这人还算自信  我可能会因此心灵受伤的
My feelings might have even been hurt if I wasn't such a self-confident individual.
不知道你们有没有注意到  我可是短裤万搭型男
I don't know if you noticed, but I'm killing these shorts.
先生  我们在找卢克
Sir, we're looking for Luke...
他攻击了混血营  还绑走我们的朋友
because he attacked Camp Half-Blood and kidnapped our friend.
我们需要你帮忙  我们已经为时不多了
And we really need your help, and we don't have a lot of time.
你们为彼此接话这点煞是可爱呢
That's really cute, how you finish each other's sentences.
跟我来
Follow.
喜欢这条领带吗  我刚买的  当然是爱马仕的
You like this tie? I just bought it. Herms, of course.
你们看
Check it out.
高科技分类  处理与包裹包装设施
State-of-the-art sorting, processing and packaging facility.
只要装得了的  我们就能以我一样快的速度
If you can box it, we can ship it at the speed of...
给送出去
Well, me.
我们计划明年要扩厂  现在生产空间实在不足
We have plans to expand next year. We're finding we have some space issues.
想像一下这幅场景  再加以扩大就行
So picture this, only bigger.
别碰那个
Don't touch that.
我们是奥林匹斯发展最快的企业
We're the fastest-growing Olympian industry.
虽然花了不少时间才走上正轨  但罗马可不是一天造成的
It took a while to get up and running,but Rome wasn't built in a day.
相信我   我可是亲眼目睹的
Trust me, I was there.
不好意思   先生  我们现在非常急
Excuse me, sir, we're in a bit of a hurry.
放轻松  小朋友  慢慢来嘛
Relax, my friend. Take it slow.
拜托  饶了我吧
Come on! Give me a break!
你说得倒轻松  阁下
Easy for you to say, Your Eminence.
玛莎  他可一点都不轻松  他可是快速之神
Actually, Martha, it's not easy for him. He's the god of freaking speed.
只不过他的屁股不用一辈子都黏在银棍子上
Except he's not the one whose butt is stuck to a big silver stick forever!
嘿  你们两个  我是怎么跟你们说的来着
Hey, guys, what did I say?
见到新朋友时要发出你们“嘶嘶”的声音  这样才比较有戏剧性
When we meet new people, protract your S's. it's more dramatic.
给人家留下个好印象
Makes an impression.
你这是在侮辱我  蛇才不这样“嘶嘶”地讲话
I'm personally insulted. Snakes don't talk like that.
这是老一套的思想  令人很不爽
It is a stereotype and it's offensive.
同类中有些术不正的家伙总是跟梅杜莎鬼混
Bad enough some of our relatives are hanging out with Medusa...
没事儿总爱把人变成石头就已经够丢人的了
turning people to stone.
好吧
All right.
我喜欢你的发型  要是我的头发也能像这样就好了
I love your hair. I wish my hair would do that.
对  这倒是有可能
Yeah, that will happen.
你们何不多做些有用处的事儿
Why don't you guys make yourselves useful?
用神用谷歌一下卢克  这些孩子在找他呢
Demi-Google Luke for me. These kids are looking for him.
为什么  他们想找死吗
Why? Do they have a death wish?
这不管你们的事儿  只管...
It doesn't matter. Just...
他连个请字都没对我们说
Didn't even say "please."
早就告诉过你了吧  我们本该去帮赫拉克勒斯效力的
Told you! We should have taken that job with Hercules.
它俩习惯这样了
They're an acquired taste.
卢克  我不知道该拿他怎么办了
Luke. I don't know what to do about him.
我曾试着跟他沟通  但那孩子怨念太深  总是愤世嫉俗
I've tried reaching out, but the kid's angry. He's resentful.
一记起仇来就六亲不认
And he holds a grudge like nobody's business.
想起来还真是跟她母亲一个模子里刻出来的
Just like his mother, come to think of it.
对  他对我也没什么好感
Yeah, he's not my biggest fan either.
要是你们碰到了  虽然宙斯明令禁止了 但一旦你们打起来
If you're gonna cross paths or, Zeus forbid, swords with him...
有一两件法宝来帮你们也不算什么么坏事
it wouldn't be the worst thing in the world to have a thing or two to help you out.
这可是独家收藏  保存得完好无缺呢
Collector's item, mint condition.
来自“赫拉克勒斯撞破头”第一季
From Hercules Busts Heads, Season One.
“赫拉克勒斯撞破头”
Hercules Busts Heads?
有史以来最棒的电视剧了
Best TV show ever.
所以当然也就再没了后续
So, of course, cancelled.
我从诸神淘宝上面买来的
Got this off Deity-Bay.
盖子一扭就会释出四面八方的风
You twist the cap off this,you release the winds from the four corners of the Earth.
你们说这个酷不酷
Now, you tell me that isn't cool.
哇~ 别别  不能在这里打开
Whoa! No, not in here!
这里可不行
Not in here.
天呐  乔治说的真没错  你们确实是想找死
By the gods, George was right. You do have a death wish.
好了  你们还...
Now, you're also...
你们也会用得到这玩意儿的
You're also gonna want one of these.
多谢
Thanks.
神用封箱胶带吗
Mythical box sealer?
你伤了我的心   真的  我真受伤了
You wound me. Truly, I am wounded.
我手上拿的是物件消除器  商标还未决定好
I hold in my hands a Matter Eliminator. Trademark pending.
只要你用它画出某个东西的轮廓
Anything you outline with this...
不许在这里用
Not in here.
那它立马就会不见
...will disappear.
消失掉  立刻就形成一个洞
Gone. Instant hole.
他是说用神用谷歌搜一下卢克吗
"Demi-Google Luke," he said.
我没有手指要怎么敲键盘
Except, how am I supposed to type without fingers?
你该用鼠标的
You were supposed to use the mouse!
我可是蛇  老鼠是拿来吃的
I'm a snake. I eat mice.
好吧  谢谢 找到卢克了吗
All right, thank you. Have you found Luke?
他刚刚说了谢谢吗
Did he just say "thank you"?
他肯定是口误
I'm sure it was just a lapse.
卢克在安德洛墨达（仙女座）号快艇上面
Luke's on a yacht called the Andromeda.
我们说话这会儿  快艇正通往切萨皮克海湾
It's passing by Chesapeake Beach as we speak.
多谢
Thank you.
你太~太客气了
You're so welcome.
好了  你满意了吗
There, you happy?
闭嘴
Hush.
多谢了
Thank you very much.
听着
Hey, listen...
如果你见到卢克的话
If you see Luke...
请转告他
please explain to him for me...
做父母的有时候也会犯错
that parents, we make mistakes sometimes.
他绝对有权利生我的气
He has every right to be angry at me.
但别因此就愤世嫉俗
Just, please tell him not to be angry with the world.
我不确定我说的话对他管不管用
I'm not sure if there's anything that I can say that will change him.
试试无妨
Try.
我这三千年来要说学到了什么
If it's one thing I've learned in 3000 years...
那就是绝不能放弃家人
it's you can't give up on family.
再次感谢
Thanks again.
他不会成功的
He'll never make it.
开饭了
That's lunch!
就是那个  那就是卢克的快艇
That's it. That's Luke's yacht.
我们该怎么办  游过去吗
What do we do? Swim?
这可是水
But it's water.
老爸会帮忙的
Dad will help.
嘿  老爸
Hey, Dad.
我们想救混血营跟羊男格罗弗
We're trying to save Camp Half-Blood and rescue a satyr named Grover.
我们需要你把我们送到那艘快艇那里
And we could really use your help getting to that ship out there.
波塞顿
Poseidon?
老爸
Dad?
不错的尝试  大块头
It was a nice try, big guy...
他就算不理会你也不必...
but don't be upset when he doesn't...
沮丧
...answer.
是马头鱼尾兽
It's a hippocampus.
嗨  美女
Hi, girl.
那叫你帅哥吧
Boy-
乖啊
Come here.
有些时候  你只需要开口就行
Sometimes, you just gotta ask.
我一直都是那么做的啊
All I've been doing is asking.
你上来吗
Are you coming?
当然
Yeah.
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
好了
Yeah.
驾
Giddy up!
退后一点
Back up!
退后
Back up.
多谢  老友
Thank you, friend.
泰森
Tyson.
快点儿  我们得走了
Come on, buddy. We gotta go.
你想吃糖吗
You want some sugar?
- 你看到了吗   - 没有  老兄
- Have you seen it? - No, man.
卢克给你看过了吗
Did he show it to you?
你看了到时候就知道了
Wait until you see it.
他花了很长时间才找到它
It took him long enough to find it.
那是克里斯・罗德里格斯  伊桑・中村跟莎娜・博勒加德
That's Chris Rodriguez, Ethan Nakamura, and Shana Beauregard.
卢克在召集人手
Luke's been recruiting.
这艘船很棒诶
This is a nice boat.
我们要怎么找格罗弗
How are we gonna find Grover?
卢克可能把他关在甲板下面某一个地方了
Luke is probably keeping him below deck somewhere.
比如说  监狱之类的
Like, in a brig.
波西  我不觉得快艇会有监狱
I don't think yachts have brigs, Percy.
跟我来
Follow me.
大家小心了  他说要跟他保持距离
Be careful, you guys. He said keep your distance.
我们到底还要在船上待多久
How much longer are we gonna be on this boat, anyway?
管它呢  小心就对了
Doesn't matter, just watch it.
我们是时候该闪人了
It's so time to go.
嘿  波西  波西
Hey. Percy. Percy!
泰森  你一定要搞那么大动静吗
Tyson, do you have to make so much noise?
对不起
Sorry!
克里斯
Chris?
嘿
Hey.
你们把格罗弗怎么了
What have you done with Grover?
格罗弗
Grover?
你最不该操心的就是格罗弗
Grover's the least of your worries.
猜猜谁来了
Guess who's here.
天大的惊喜啊  这不是我最爱的两位表亲吗
What a surprise. If it isn't my two favorite cousins.
是三个
Three.
我也是波塞顿的儿子
I'm a son of Poseidon, too.
那就搞笑了  因为波塞顿没别的混血儿子
That's funny, because Poseidon doesn't have any other half-blood sons.
我是独眼巨人
I'm a Cyclops.
我用了喷雾
Mist.
不是吧
You don't say.
好久不见
It's been a long time.
气色不错嘛
You look good.
格罗弗在哪儿
Where's Grover?
格罗弗  格罗弗
Grover, Grover.
他现在应该抵达魔兽之海了
He should be in the Sea of Monsters right about now.
我派他跟几个朋友先过去了  我们的时间挺紧的
I sent him on ahead with some friends. We're kind of on the clock.
等等  你不...
Wait, you're not...
你不只阻止我们拿到金羊毛
You're not just trying to stop us from getting the Fleece.
我也需要金羊毛
I need it, too.
有个东西只有靠金羊毛才能救活
I got something only the Fleece can revive.
那可不只是一棵树
And it's not a tree.
你们想看看吗
Wanna see it?
这东西可不好找
It wasn't easy to find.
我得亲自爬过冥界至深至暗的深渊
I had to crawl through the depths of Tartarus itself.
还要去克利夫兰市
And then Cleveland.
这是克隆那斯的遗体
The remains of Kronos.
泰坦的始祖  奥林匹亚山十二神之父
The original Titan, father to the Olympians.
有了金羊毛的帮助  他就会摧毁奥林匹斯
And with the Fleece's help, destroyer of Olympus.
同时也会摧毁世界
And the world.
为了报复你老爸  你甚至不惜摧毁全世界吗
You'd destroy the whole world just to get back at your dad?
诸神打倒他们的父母
The Olympians overthrew their parents.
现在轮到我们了
It's just our turn.
我们见过你老爸
We met your father.
他说他知道自己犯了错
He said that he knows that he made mistakes.
他让我们转告你别这么愤怒
He told us to tell you to not be so angry.
真的吗
Really?
他甚至都不敢亲口告诉我吗
And he couldn't even tell me himself.
听起来二耳熟吗
Does that sound familiar?
把他们带去监狱
Take them to the brig.
走吧  快点
Let's go. Come on.
塔利亚是你的朋友  她为你牺牲了自己
Thalia was your friend! She sacrificed herself for you.
你跟泰森搞在一起  还敢拿塔利亚的事跟我说教
You're gonna lecture me about Thalia when you're hanging around with him?
最让我失望的就是你
You disappoint me the most.
我跟你说他有监狱吧
I told you he had a brig.
你怎么能信任泰森
How can you trust him?
他可能是故意弄那么大动静的
He was probably making all that noise on purpose.
他想让卢克抓到我们
He wanted Luke to catch us.
你为什么总针对泰森
What do you have against Tyson anyway?
他可是独眼巨人
He's a Cyclops.
我想官方用语称之为是“眼部受损”
I think the politically correct term is "ocularly impaired."
管他们叫什么  他们又邪恶又危险
Who cares? They're vicious and they're dangerous.
对啊  真是太邪恶了
Yeah, vicious.
我们得离开这儿
We have to get out of here.
要怎么做
How?
找个东西抓稳了
Just hang on to something.
好吧  我要来拿你了
All right, here we go.
拜托  拜托  拜托
Come on, come on, come on!
怎么回事
What's going on?
波西想害死我们
Percy's trying to kill us.
我想他快成功了
I think it's working.
你拿到了吗
You got it?
易如反掌
Piece of cake.
我觉得我要吐了
I think I'm gonna vomit.
这要吐了
Yep.
这东西要怎么用
So, how does this work?
我也不知道  这是我第一次使用神用封箱胶带
I don't know. It's my first mythical tape gun.
就跟赫尔墨斯说的那样
Just like Hermes said...
立马就会形成了一个洞
"instant hole."
快到救生艇那里去
Go to the lifeboat.
把引擎关掉
Kill the engines.
这一记是替格罗弗打的
That was for Grover.
抓住他
Grab him!
我们逮到他了
We got him!
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
别在我的屋顶走来走去
Don't walk on my roof.
波西  加入我的队伍吧
Join me, Percy.
这是你命中注定的  你摆脱不了预言
It's what you were meant to do. You can't escape that prophecy.
让我们一起干一番大事给老爸们看看吧
Let's show both of our fathers.
你说得很吸引人
It's tempting.
你还真是个天才啊  真的
That's genius. Really.
但我想还是算了
But I think I'll pass.
别又这样
Not this again.
快走
Go!
- 你要留下来吗  - 我随后就到
- Are you staying? - I'll be right behind you.
也来试试你吧
May as well.
杰克逊  够了
Jackson, enough.
你现在处在劣势
You're on the losing side.
在我看来可不是这样
Not from where I stand.
挺聪明的嘛
Smart.
我是智慧女神之女  不记得吗
Goddess of wisdom's daughter, remember?
我记得呢
I remember.
我们的同盟跟羊男在寻找金羊毛方面还是领先于他们
Our allies and the satyr still have a head start on the Fleece.
克隆那斯大人  我们一定会让你复活的
We will resurrect you, Lord Kronos.
你会尝到复仇的滋味的
You will know vengeance.
那些轻视我们的十二主神一定会尝到死亡的滋味
And the Olympians who scorned us will know death.
你该补一下喷雾了
Maybe you should reapply.
喷雾退了吗
It wore off?
对
Yeah.
拜托
Come on.
别啊
Oh, no.
嘿
Hey.
你想掌舵吗
Do you want to steer for a while?
谢谢
Thank you.
从来没人愿意信任我做任何事
Nobody's ever trusted me with anything before.
是因为你没办法判断景深吗
Is that because of your lack of depth perception?
是因为大家怕你吗
Is it because they're scared of you?
有一天  我当时在山里
I was in the mountains one day...
后来来了几个露营的童子军
and some campers, Boy Scouts, showed up.
他们看到我之后下的大声尖叫
And when they saw me, they screamed.
四处逃窜
They ran.
我很确定我当时是微笑着的
And I'm pretty sure I smiled.
但大家看到我都把我当成怪物
People look at me, and they see a monster.
有时候  我在想  或许他们是对的
Sometimes, I think maybe they're right.
你不是怪物  别对自己那么残忍
You're not a monster. Don't be so hard on yourself.
你当然说起来很轻松
Easy for you to say.
什么意思
What do you mean?
你从来没怀疑过或看不起过自己
You never doubt yourself or think you're less than you are.
谢谢你  哥哥
Thank you, brother.
到这边来  慢慢打开
Come here. Open it slowly.
慢一点
Slowly.
速度放慢一点  好吗
Hey, just take it slow. Slow, okay?
我连一般的保温瓶都不敢交付给他
I wouldn't have trusted him with a normal thermos.
他做得还行啊  我是说
He seems okay.I mean...
我实在搞不懂你对他有什么偏见
I really don't get what your problem with him is.
因为你不了解我对他们有什么了解
Because you don't know what I know about them.
塔利亚
Thalia!
是一个独眼巨人杀了她
A Cyclops killed her.
他的同类杀了塔利亚
His kind killed Thalia.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我之前一直不知道
I never knew.
我也不喜欢谈这个话题
Well, it's not something I like talking about.
不管如何  那是很久之前的事了
And anyway, it was a long time ago.
那是什么
What is that?
魔兽之海
It's the Sea of Monsters.
我们干嘛停下来
Why are we stopping?
我应该用两只手来的
I should have used two hands.
那你觉得该用几只手
You think?
你在生我的气吗
Are you mad at me?
没有  我不是生你的气
No, not at you.
告诉我那些不是鲨鱼
Tell me those aren't sharks.
那些不是鲨鱼
Those aren't sharks.
快划  快点划
Paddle! Paddle!
对  是鲨鱼还反而还好了
Yeah, sharks would be better.
是卡律布迪斯（波塞顿与盖亚的女儿）
It's Charybdis.
卡律布... 什么
Charyb... What?
她负责镇守魔兽之海
She guards the Sea of Monsters.
波西
Percy!
我的能力不管用了
It's not working!
魔兽之海可能不归波塞顿管
The Sea of Monsters might not be in Poseidon's domain.
抓稳了
Hold on!
我们在哪儿
Where are we?
闻起来像胃的味道
Smells like the stomach.
小心脚下
Watch your step.
这是什么东西
What is this stuff?
我觉得你不会想知道的
I don't think you want to know.
肯定没有比这更糟的死法了
This has to be the worst way to die, ever.
对  所有在百慕大三角消失的东西
Yeah, everything that disappears in the Bermuda Triangle...
最终都会来到这里
this is where they end up.
拜托
Come on!
听起来好像是克拉丽丝
That sounded like Clarissa.
不  不可能是她
No, it couldn't be her.
你们这群愚蠢的大笨蛋
You ridiculously stupid morons.
是她没错  就是她
No, it's her. -It's her.
你这个白痴
You idiot!
你最好让我的电网正常运作  否则我就把你的头塞进去
Better keep my electric grid up and running, or I'll plug your head into it!
克拉丽丝  嘿
Clarissa! Hey!
杰克逊  你来这里干嘛
Jackson? What are you doing here?
我们跟你们一样被吞了
We got swallowed up, just like you.
好棒的船啊
Nice ship.
我老爸作战留了一大堆这样的船下来
My dad's got tons of this stuff left over from wars throughout history.
不开船就得开越战留下直升机  我觉得船比较实用
It was either this or a Huey from Vietnam. I figured a boat would be more practical.
怎么回事
What's going on?
你认为在胃里面还会有什么事
Pretty much exactly what you think goes on inside of a stomach.
你说的对
You're right.
这真的是最糟的死法
That really is the worst way to die.
里尔登
Reardon!
我的引擎他娘的是怎么回事  弄好了吗
What in Hades is going on with my engine? Is it ready yet?
小姐  快好了 他们正在努力
Almost, ma'am. They're working on it.
等等  你的船员是僵尸吗
Wait, your crew is zombies?
他们是“已故南方联盟的水手”
They prefer "dead Confederate sailors
“向阿瑞斯致敬奉献了生命”
whose lives have been given in tribute to Ares."
不过叫僵尸也无所谓啦
But "zombies" is fine.
里尔登  枪准备好了吗  快点  我马上就要
Reardon! Gun! Faster! Now!
船长  枪已备妥上膛
Gun is hot, Cap'n. Locked and loaded.
瞄准那个绞肉机
Aim it at that meat grinder.
等等... 你想用枪来打它吗
Wait, wait. You want to shoot that thing with this?
你还有更好的主意吗  有的话就快说
Do you have a better idea? Because now would be the time.
嘿  克拉丽丝
Hey, Clarissa.
干嘛
What?
你会开船吗
Can you steer the ship?
不会  我才刚接受完驾驶员课程教育  废话  我当然会开船
No. I just finished driver's ed. Yes, of course, I can steer a ship.
这个嘛...
Well...
我们何不让它胃痛一下
why don't we give her a stomach ache?
然后我们司机从肠子逃走
We'll escape through the gut.
要是没先被它给弄死  这招可能会管用
It just might work if it doesn't kill us first.
你负责驾驶  我来负责开枪
You steer, I'll shoot.
所有人员到甲板下去
All hands below deck!
波西  祝你好运
Good luck, Percy.
所有人员到甲板底下  这不是演习
All hands below deck. This is not a drill!
快点  兄弟们  快进去
Come on, boys. Get in there.
这还是我的任务
This is still my quest.
不准把我的任务搞砸了  杰克逊
Do not screw this up for me, Jackson.
你应该对自己吃的食物多留点神
You should watch what you eat.
快走
Go!
这个不是在开玩笑
No kidding, genius.
最好能管用
I hope this works.
- 别忘了  - 别忘了什么
- Just don't forget. - Forget what?
这可全都是你的主意
This is all your idea.
拜托  拜托
Come on, come on.
- 我们成功了  - 我成功了
- We did it! - I did it!
听好  全速前进
Listen up. Full power to the screws.
嘿  你们还好吗
Hey. are you guys all right?
你简直太棒了
That was amazing.
你得有信心 知道吗
You have to have faith, right?
再加一座大炮  我们一定会找到格罗弗的
And a cannon. We'll find Grover.
伊克那提呢
Where is lchneutae?
你现在想起伊克那提了
Now you miss lchneutae?
我们碰到希拉那个长着九个头的女妖
We ran into Scylla, that multi-headed Hydra thing.
他就说“我来搞定它”
He said, "I got this."
也算是有名的遗言
Famous last words.
船长  动力系统全部恢复了
We've restored full power, Cap'n.
- 朝哪个方向前进  - 西北方
- Heading? - Northwest.
你确定吗
Are you sure about that?
对  我确定  怎么  你有什么疑问吗
Yes, I'm sure about that. Why, do you have a problem?
对啊  你有什么疑问吗
Yeah, you got a problem?
我认为你的南方邦联战舰现在正在朝往佛罗里达西棕榈滩走
I think your Confederate warship is heading to West Palm Beach, Florida.
怎么了
What is it?
我知道这听起来很夸张  但这有点像我的阅读困难症
I know this sounds insane, but it's kind of like my dyslexia.
我看不懂希腊文  却看得懂地图上的经纬线
But instead of being able to read Greek, I can see map lines.
三十  三十一  七十五  十二
30. 31, 75,12.
等等  这些数字是...
Wait, that's the numbers from the...
是那些没眼睛的神经病司机说的
From the crazy, eyeless taxi drivers.
这些是座标
They're coordinates.
水小子总算搞清楚了
Waterboy figured it out.
他叫你神经病呢
And he called you crazy.
事实上  他是在叫你神经病
Actually, he called you crazy.
嘿  眼睛看着路
Hey, eye on the road.
北纬三十  三十一度
30, 31 degrees north...
西经七十五 十二度
75,12 degrees west.
波吕斐摩斯跟金羊毛就在那里
That's where Polyphemus and the Fleece are.
改变航道   朝西南方前进
Change course. Southwest.
遵~命
Aye.
抱歉
Sorry.
发现陆地了
Land ho!
波吕斐摩斯住在游乐场里面吗
Polyphemus lives in an amusement park?
不  他住在一个岛上
No, he lives on an island.
但女妖锡西觉得
But the goddess Circe thought building
在岛上盖游乐场是个不错的主意
an amusement park on top of it was a good idea.
其实根本不是
It really wasn't.
发生什么事了
What happened?
剪彩那天...
Opening day...
来了一堆可口的混血儿  跟一个饿极了的独眼巨人
long lines of savory half-bloods and one hungry Cyclops.
这可对生意影响不好
Bad for business.
我马上就掉头
I'll just turn us right around then.
找个地方停船
Find us a place to dock.
我就怕她要这么说
I was afraid she was gonna say that.
我想独眼巨人确实是会影响生意
I guess the Cyclops was bad for business.
当初谁知道啊
Who knew?
我们没时间搜查整个游乐场
We don't have time to search this whole place.
我觉得没有必要
I don't think we have to.
“直坠死亡”
"Plummet of Death"?
还真是含蓄
That's subtle.
看来是有只庞然大物从这里通过啊
It looks like something really big went through there.
不知道  我觉得看起来不像是独眼巨人
I don't know. It doesn't really scream "Cyclops" to me.
至少不用排队
At least there's no line.
看着挺好玩的嘛
Sweet ride.
可能需要推一把
Might need a push.
我们走吧
Here we go.
泰森  放开我的手
Tyson? Let go of my hand.
对不起
Sorry.
世界真小啊
It's a small world after all
你们两个闭嘴行吗
Could you two just shut up?
坐稳了
Hold on!
大家没事吧
Is everybody okay?
我还以为会更好玩的
I thought that would be more fun.
我想我懂了格罗弗之前为什么会那么担心了
I think I get what Grover was so worried about.
这一定是波吕斐摩斯在奥德修斯从特洛伊战争归来时
This must be the boulder Polyphemus used to trap Odysseus...
用来困住他的那块大石头
when he was returning from the Trojan War.
没错   我也知道这事儿
Yeah, that's right. I know stuff.
格罗弗
Grover!
够了
Enough!
我再也受不了了
I can't take this anymore.
这都已经两天了
It's been two days!
控制住你的情绪  控制情绪
Calm your temper! Calm your temper!
自从你带来那几个混血人之后  我就再也没吃过一顿像样的饭了
I haven't had a decent meal since those half-bloods you brought!
这根蠢毛应该能把羊男吸引过来才对
And this stupid fleece is supposed to lure satyrs!
你有在这里看到任何羊男吗
Do you see any satyrs around here?
我饿得眼睛都花了
This hunger is making my eyesight worse.
要是你不是独眼巨人的话
I could just eat you.
我就把你给吃了
If you weren't a Cyclops.
格罗弗
Grover!
嘿  到这儿来
Hey! Come here!
波西
Percy?
嘿
Hey!
你干嘛穿裙子
Why are you wearing a dress?
我现在日子过得真的很惨
I'm having a really bad day!
嘿嘿嘿  不许放到网上
Hey, hey, hey! Do not let that go viral!
抱歉  要是不这样做没人会信我的话
Sorry, there's no way the other kids would believe me otherwise.
这是伪装啦
This is a disguise.
他有点瞎  以为我是独眼巨人女佣
The guy's half-blind. He thinks I'm a Cyclops chambermaid.
我可是在这儿展现疯狂的生存技巧
I'm showing mad survival skills, here.
你还大秀美腿呢
And not a small amount of leg.
一点都不好笑
Funny.
我在尽量想办法拖延时间  好从他那儿把金羊毛给偷过来
I was trying to stay uneaten long enough to figure out how to get the Fleece off of him.
那你成功了吗
So, did you?
你觉得我成功了的话还会穿成这样吗
Do you think I'd still be dressed like this if I did?
你很漂亮啊
It's a good look.
谢了  泰森
Thanks, Tyson.
小独独  我给你弄点喝的
Clopsies, how about I cook you something to drink...
消消火如何
to calm your nerves?
我都不知道该做什么了
I don't know what to do anymore.
走  快走
Go! Go!
金羊毛以前天天都会吸引大把羊男过来
This fleece used to lure satyrs every day.
现在居然沦落到得吃自己的羊了
Now things are so bad, I even had to eat my own sheep.
整群都吃光了
The whole flock!
不过它们的肉还是非常鲜美的
They were tender, though.
你要是让我掉下了  我保证跟会你没完
Drop me, and I promise you'll never hear the end of it.
你有闻到什么味道吗
Do you smell something?
像是混血儿的味道
Smells like half-bloods!
混血儿
Half-bloods!
快起来  快点  我猜对了
Get up, quick! I was right!
你们给我待在那而别动
You stay right there!
女佣  快去生火
Woman, get a fire going!
这可不妙
That's not good!
仔细想了想...
On second thought...
还是生吃你们的好
I'll just eat you raw!
嘿
Hey!
你好
Hi ya!
我叫泰森  你好吗
My name's Tyson. How are you?
他们是我的朋友
These guys are my friends...
我希望能跟你聊聊
so I was hoping, maybe, we could talk.
独眼巨人之间打对话
You know, Cyclops to Cyclops.
你这个独眼小家伙
You pissant with one eye!
嘿  你这样讲真是太不友好了
Hey! Not nice!
你才不是独眼巨人呢
You're no Cyclops!
你背叛了同类
You're a traitor to your kind!
说实话...
To be honest...
什么
Huh? What?
他才跟我是同类
He's my kind.
你真让让我作呕
You disgust me.
想跑哪去
Going somewhere?
我觉得你貌似拿了我的东西
I think you've got something of mine.
安娜贝丝
Annabeth!
克拉丽丝
Clarissa!
给我回来  你这个小流氓
Get back here, you punk!
呦  小独独
Yo, Clopsies!
我不干了
'Quit!
等一下  你是男的
Wait, you're a dude?
那就说得通了
Well, that explains a lot.
- 跟他说再见吧  - 好吧 再见
-say goodbye. - Okay. Goodbye!
你们这群乳臭未干的毛头小子  我一定要把你们大卸八块
You deceitful little brats! I'll tear off your flesh!
快点  走  快走
Come on! Go, go!
把金羊毛还给我
Give me that fleece!
你们死定了
You're dead!
我要把你们全都给杀光
I'm gonna kill all of you!
你们听到了吗
Do you hear me?
快给我回来
Get back here!
我们的任务很成功
We rocked that quest.
对  绝对的
Yeah, we totally did.
我不晓得你们有这么强呢
I didn't know you guys had it in you!
没错
Yes.
干得不错
Well done.
干得好  我很感激你们的行为
It's nice work. I really appreciate it.
东西我就收下了
I'll take that.
妄想
I don't think so.
随你便吧
Suit yourself.
换做你的话也会这么做的
You'd do it for me.
不~
No!
记住...
Just remember...
本来不必闹得如此下场的
it didn't have to end this way.
这全都怪你
This one's on you.
退下  小家伙
Down, boy!
你们应该觉得自己幸运
You should consider yourselves lucky.
这可是酝酿了几千年之久
This has been millennia in the making.
你们全部能有幸亲眼目睹
And you all get to see it.
你以前是我们这一边的人
You used to be one of us!
可我之后醒悟了
And then I woke up.
波西  克隆那斯复活的话  世界就完蛋了
Percy, if Kronos comes back, that's it. Game over.
波西
Percy.
我从没叫过他一声弟弟
I never called him "brother."
他只想做我的弟弟而已
All he ever wanted was a brother...
但我只顾着我自己
but I was too wrapped up in myself.
这下好了  金羊毛落到卢克手上
And now Luke has the Fleece...
因为我拱手让给了他
because I gave it to him.
正如神谕所说的那样  我毁了奥林匹斯
I destroy Olympus, just like the Oracle said.
别管什么神谕了
Forget the Oracle.
你担心自己的命运  那就自己去创造一个新的
You're worried about your destiny? Then write a new one.
你生气波塞顿不理你  那就做给他看  用行动告诉他错了
You're angry at Poseidon for ignoring you? Then show him why he shouldn't.
泰森的事情让你难过
You're upset about Tyson?
那就别让他白白送死
Then make sure he didn't die for nothing.
她说的对
She's right.
什么
What?
好话不说两遍
There's no way you're getting me to repeat that.
波西  俺安娜贝丝是说
What Annabeth is saying, Perce...
你还有我们
is that we're with you.
有事尽管开口就好
Just give the word.
为什么是我
Why me?
是谁选我当领队的
I mean, who voted me leader?
被亲生儿子背叛的克隆那斯当然
Lord Kronos, he who was betrayed by his sons...
请听被父亲背叛的人一言
hear now the words of one betrayed by his father.
我恳请你... 复活吧
I bid you... rise.
格罗弗
Grover!
手给我
Hands.
尽量别砍掉了  我对它们可是有感情的
Try not to cut them off. I'm pretty attached to them.
我得去拿回金羊毛
I have to get to the Fleece.
那我们该怎么做
So, what are we supposed to do?
对啊
Right.
杰克逊  我知道你在水里能呼吸
I know you can breathe under water, Jackson.
可是你这样还能再呼吸吗
But can you breathe like this?
嗨 哥哥
Hi, Brother!
到底怎么...
What the...?
水的缘故
The water.
水把我治好了
It healed me.
我可是波塞顿之子
Son of Poseidon.
谢谢你
Thank you...
弟弟
Brother.
他复活了
He rises.
主人
Master!
是我让你复活的
I brought you back!
主人
My Lord!
我是卢克
It's Luke!
卢克・卡斯特兰
Luke Castellan!
您的曾孙
Your great-grandson!
我的最爱
My favorite.
格罗弗
Grover!
这是诅咒之剑
It's the cursed blade!
“诅咒之剑将会夺取”
"...cursed blade shall reap."
想知道是谁给我的这把剑吗
You want to know who gave me this sword?
就是原本用这把剑杀掉你的神
The god that killed you with it in the first place!
我的父亲
My father.
波西・杰克逊
Percy Jackson...
你的命运早已注定
your destiny was written long ago.
不~
No!
我的命运要靠自己来编写
I make my own destiny.
混血儿
Half-blood!
你刚好赶上我的晚餐时间
Just in time for dinner.
谢了 老爸
Thanks, Dad.
波西
Percy.
安娜贝丝
Annabeth!
格罗弗
Grover!
安娜贝丝
Annabeth!
不  不要
No, no!
至少我可以跟塔利亚相聚了
At least I'll be with Thalia in Elysium.
过来  快把金羊毛给我
Come here. Give me the Fleece!
快点...快点
Come on! Come on.
快点
Come on.
我们要创造自己的命运   不是吗  那就做给我看呐
We make our own destinies, right? So show me.
我对你有信心
I have faith in you.
不不不  拜托  做给我看啊
No, no. Come on, show me.
给我看呐
Show me.
拜托
Come on.
安妮
Annie.
发生什么事了
What happened?
没事了
Don't worry about it.
如果今晚还有人想死的话
If anyone else wants to die tonight...
至少我们有这个
at least we have this.
嘿  你还活着
Hey. You're alive.
对
Yeah.
你为波西所做的事  真的是...
What you did for Percy,that was um...
一点都不邪恶一点都不危险
that was not so vicious and dangerous.
谢了
Thanks.
不
No.
该谢谢你才对
Thank you.
你知道吗  泰森
You know what, Tyson?
营区里有很多两只眼睛的人都做不到你之前所做的事
I know a lot of campers with two eyes who couldn't do what you did.
- 嘿  克拉丽丝  - 干嘛
- Hey, Clarissa. - What?
走吧  大块头  等我们回到营区  我请你喝花蜜咖啡
Come on, big guy. We get back to camp, the nectar's on me.
你遇见过宁芙吗
Have you met the nymphs?
这是你的任务
This was your quest.
没有你我根本做不到
I couldn't have done it without you.
我认为你才是该有幸
I think you should be the one who gets to...
将这份金羊毛带回营地
...do the honors.
回来吧  塔利亚
Here you go, Thalia.
克拉丽丝  克拉丽丝 克拉丽丝
Clarissa! Clarissa! Clarissa!
要花蜜咖啡吗
Nectar?
如果你没喝过...
If you haven't had...
就算是枉在世上走一遭了
...you haven't lived.
你知道吗
You know what?
你再也不需要墨镜了
You don't need these anymore.
好了  这样就好多了
There, that's better.
你看起来很开心嘛
You seem happy.
我只是庆幸能够放下预言的重担了
I'm just relieved to have that whole prophecy thing off my shoulders.
我不感完全断定  不行
I'm not altogether sure it is, Percy.
你表现得非常棒  但你依然还是...
You've done wonderfully, but you are still the only living human child...
波塞顿  哈迪斯跟宙斯仅存的人类后代
of Poseidon, Hades, or Zeus.
更何况...
Besides...
神谕指的很有可能并不是
it's quite possible the Oracle wasn't referring
波吕斐摩斯岛上会发生的事
to what would unfold on Polyphemus' island.
我是说  在你满二十岁生日之前  还可能会发生很多事情
I'm just saying, a lot can happen between now and your 20th birthday.
我不是那个意思
That's not really what I meant.
我是说发现我的命运
What I meant was finding out you have a destiny...
就跟发现自己有个同父异母的独眼巨人弟弟一样
is a lot like finding out you have a half-brother who's a Cyclops.
可能并不如我之前想的那么糟
It might not be as bad as you think.
波西  波西
Percy! Percy!
波西
Percy!
安娜贝丝昨晚守护树的时候
Annabeth was guarding the tree last night...
发生了一件事
and something happened.
波西
Percy.
- 金羊毛...  - 发生什么事了
- The Fleece! - What happened?
它比我们想的作用还要强大
It was even more powerful than we thought.
快点  帮帮她
Come on, help her.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是波西   没事了  一切都没事儿了
Percy. Everything's all right, it's okay.
我做了个非常奇怪的梦
I had the strangest dream.
是吗
Yeah?
就好像快要死了
Like I was dying.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
我是塔利亚  宙斯之女
I'm Thalia, daughter of Zeus.
又有一个三大主神的后裔存活
Another living child of the eldest gods.
或许那不是我
Maybe it wasn't me.
或许神谕一开始所指指的就是塔利亚
Maybe the Oracle meant Thalia all along.
她会是我们的救世主
Could she be our salvation?
还是会导致我们的毁灭呢
Or the cause of our destruction?
谢谢观赏  更多字幕请关注“幕雨字幕组”新浪微博
Thanks for watching!